<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>af-FAB-le</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on af-FAB-le</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>CCBY-4.0 Clara Rigaud and Yvonne Jansen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 16:44:53 +0210</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Capush] fixed camera unit</title><link>/capush/fixed-cam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 16:44:53 +0210</pubDate><guid>/capush/fixed-cam/</guid><description>The fixed cam is a basic unit type whose main functionality is to provide access to a networked camera. For our proof of concept implementation, we selected a Raspberry PI as the base unit as it has a small form factor while providing the convenience of a full Linux distribution. These boards come equipped with a range of wired and wireless network connections, and are often readily available in many fabrication workshops.</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>/post/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 12:50:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>/post/intro/</guid><description>This post will explain a bit what af-FAB-le is about.</description></item><item><title>[Capush] pan-tilt camera unit</title><link>/capush/pan-tilt-cam/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 16:44:53 +0203</pubDate><guid>/capush/pan-tilt-cam/</guid><description>The pan-tilt camera is an extension of the fixed camera. It is also installed permanently in the environment but its camera is mounted on a pan-tilt assembly enabling rotations around the pan and tilt axis for more control over the focus area. The control of the pan-tilt assembly can be automatic or manual. The latter lets makers control the orientation of the camera either through physical manipulations or through a (virtual) joystick interface displayed on a computer or smartphone&amp;rsquo;s screen.</description></item><item><title>[Capush] clamp camera unit</title><link>/capush/clamp-cam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 16:44:53 +0202</pubDate><guid>/capush/clamp-cam/</guid><description>A clamp camera is a mobile extension of the pan-tilt camera. It includes a battery pack and is mounted on a clamp, so that it can easily be moved and attached in the environment in different locations to get different points of view. This unit can thus be used to capture a scene from flexible points of view, providing the makers with a quick and simple way to set up their scene.</description></item><item><title>[Capush] head-mounted camera unit</title><link>/capush/head-mounted-cam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 16:44:53 +0201</pubDate><guid>/capush/head-mounted-cam/</guid><description>The head-mounted camera is an extension of the pan-tilt camera mounted on a headset, similar to the clamp but worn by the person, enabling a first person viewpoint capture. By attaching the unit once to the head, the maker can move around in the space wearing the head-mounted camera to go from an activity to another.</description></item><item><title>[Capush] table-bot unit</title><link>/capush/table-bot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 16:44:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>/capush/table-bot/</guid><description>Table bot is a pan-tilt camera mounted on a small robot. Either the maker or the robot can decide the best position and orientation for this camera unit. In particular, the robot can track pieces (e.g. circuit board) or tools (solder) and move around on a table to maintain the distance between the objects of interest and the camera constant.
Bill of material Alphabot2-pi</description></item><item><title>A Summary of our Survey Results</title><link>/survey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/survey/</guid><description>In May/June 2021 we ran a survey advertised by email to many Fablabs around the world. We received 66 responses from people characterized by the following demographics. An overview of the demographics of our respondents.</description></item></channel></rss>